Konrad Wroński

Amersfoort, Netherlands | +48604860925 | kw10.1916@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/konrad-wroński

PROFILE

Curious, creative and eager to learn professional with a passion for data analysis, machine learning and econometrics. Demonstrated expertise in Python, R and SAS programming, machine learning and econometric modelling. Equipped with 3 years of experience at SAS Institute, contributing to the development and implementation of data analytics solutions.

EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATIONS

Masters of Applied Data Science

September 2023 - June 2024

Utrecht University, Netherlands

Electives:

- Text and media analytics
- Spatial data analysis and simulation modelling
- Personalisation for public media
- Human network analysis

Bachelor of Quantitative Economics and Information Systems

April 2021

Warsaw School of Economics, Poland

Microsoft Certified: Azure AI Engineer AssociateDecember 2022Microsoft Certified: Power Platform FundamentalsDecember 2022Microsoft Certified: Azure FundamentalsDecember 2022SAS Certified Specialist: Base Programming Using SAS 9.4May 2021

SKILLS

- Programming Languages: Python, R, SAS, SQL, VBA, DAX, OOP Programming
- Data Analysis Tools: Power BI, Power Automate, Power Apps, QGIS, Excel
- Machine Learning: Tensorflow, Keras, Natural Language Processing (LLMs), Deep Learning
- Platforms: Azure Cloud, Kafka, Git
- Languages: Polish (native speaker), English C1 (IELTS 8.0), Spanish A2/B1, Dutch A1

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Systems Engineer

April 2021 – Present

SAS Institute, Warsaw (Remote), Full-time

- Built an internal automation solution in Power Automate along with reporting in Power BI that accelerated PoC approvals by 40%
- Developed a credit risk web application integrated with machine learning models built in both SAS and Python. Deployed the application on Azure App Service, utilizing Azure Machine Learning for model management and scoring. Implemented CI/CD pipelines using Azure DevOps.
- Prepared detailed demos to showcase the capabilities of SAS Event Stream Processing, highlighting integrations with Azure Event Hubs, Kafka, and RESTful APIs.
- Programmed and designed employee development tracker using Power Apps. The solution increased training completion rates by 45% through automated reminders and progress tracking, providing managers with real-time updates via Power BI
- Created a comprehensive Python and SQL code "task" within the SAS environment, enabling users to preprocess data and generate ML models without writing any code.

Head Coach

September 2017 – April 2022

Socatots Poland, Warsaw

• Football coach of 4 children groups

PROJECTS

Project 1: Music and painting reinvented

Link: https://github.com/kw10-uw/GIT_PAINT

Technology used: Python, Ruby, SonicPi

- Innovative approach to link painting and making music
- Developed working prototype using Python and SonicPi
- Final goal to create a physical product in which this application is running using RaspberryPi

Project 2: Image Clustering

Link: https://rpubs.com/konrad10w/gems cluster pca

Technology used: R

- Clustered images of gemstones using CLARA method
- Obtained average color of each gemstone in RGB scale
- Used dimension reduction techniques and observed changes to silhouette

Project 3: Basket analysis

Link: https://rpubs.com/konrad10w/restaurant_basket

Technology used: R

- Basket analysis on restaurant data using Eclat and Apriori algorithms
- Distinguished sets of products often bought together (Eclat algorithm)
- Assessed rules quality of Apriori algorithm using Jaccard index

Project 4: Toxicity detection (NLP) (Utrecht University Project)

Link: https://www.academia.edu/114790128/Addressing_class_imbalance_problem_in_toxicity_detection_task?source=swp_share

Technology used: Python

- Used different sampling techniques like SMOTE and ADASYN
- Used two machine learning models: Logistic Regression and XGBoost
- Assessed recall improvement on toxicity detection with different sampling techniques

Project 5: Light Pollution spatial analysis (Utrecht University Group Project)

Technology used: QGIS, Python

- NASA Dataset
- Data preparation made in QGIS (aggregating raster and vector layers)
- Created machine learning models to assess socio-economic factors influencing light pollution